DAVID HEW-WING

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

davidhewwing.io

4 647-924-9815

♀ 333 Friel Street

DavidHewWing

I am a Software Engineer with over four years of experience. I build clean code at a timely speed. I have strong knowledge and outstanding experience in Android Development (Java and Kotlin), Web Development and Java. I believe Software Engineers have the ability to change the world. This fact, the feeling when someone is benefiting from your product and the always-changing nature of the industry, keeps me passionate and innovative.

Skills

FLUENT - LANGUAGES

Java

Python

HTML

Javascript

XML Git

AngularJS

- ·

Ruby

Angular

RxJS

NgRX

Kotlin

FLUENT - TECHNOLOGIES

Eclipse

Android Studio

Parse.io

Firebase.io

AWS

Bitnami

Bitbucket

JIRA Github

Confluence

DECTE LIMIT

RESTful Webservices

TFS

Linux

PuTTy

FAMILIAR TECHNOLOGIES AND LANGUAGES

Docker

Nagios

Kubernetes

Puppet

Education

University of Ottawa BASc Software Engineering

2nd Year Undergraduate

Employment

JSI Telecom

Jan. 2019 to May 2019

Software Engineer Intern

- Web Application Developer and Infrastructure Maintenance on the JSI 4Sight Suite.

- Squashed bug quick to increase velocity 200% upon arrival.
- AGILE development using TFS.
- Worked with Angular, AngularJS, Ruby, Linux.

Canadian Food Inspection Agency

Ottawa, ON

Kanata, Ontario

Mobile Developer Intern

May 2018 to Aug. 2018

Sept. 2017 to Current

- Full-stack engineer responsible technological direction for a five-member mobile development team.
- Firebase.io, ParseServer, AWS, Bitnami and SQLite to organize data.
- Attended and contributed client meetings, discussing technical and business requirements.
- Android Development, Java, Git.

Projects

GamesHub

Jan. 2019 to Current

Feb. 2019 to Current

Feb. 2019 to Mar. 2019

- A Web Application that allows to play simple board games, etc.
- Angular, NgRX, Git

Personal Website

- davidhewwing.io

- Always updating the content

- Angular, Git

SafeChat

- uses Google AutoML and Angular to determine if a phrase can be harmful.
- potentially can filter out toxic/harmful phrases in a group chat or event page.
- Angular, Pandas, AutoML, and more.

CFIA Calculator May 2018 to Sept. 2018

- Calculator for the Canadian Food Inspection Agency for Android.
- Allowed for streamlined risk-based assessments.
- Created wireframes and prototypes.
- Met with clients to understand technical and business requirements.

Zork: Text Based Adventure

Jan. 2017 to Aug. 2017

- My take on Zork: A Text Based AdventureWorked with a team and used version control
- Java

Activities

Varsity Ultimate Frisbee

Sept. 2017 to Current

Cutter for the University of Ottawa Gee-Gees varsity ultimate team.

Volunteering

Ottawa Carleton Ultimate Association · Youth Coach

May 2018 to Aug. 2018

- Coached children U17 and U12 basic rules concepts of Ultimate Frisbee
- Worked with co-coaches to design drills, keep them organized and keep the children safe.